[
    {
        "question": "………….. are geologically the most active areas of the ocean – bed.",
        "options": [
            "Marine trenches",
            "Marine deeps",
            "Marine deposits"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Which landform of ocean floor is important from human point of view.",
        "options": [
            "Continental slope",
            "Marine trenches",
            "Continental shelf"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False Human induced material are found to be harmful to hydrosphere.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The continents are the part of ……………",
        "options": [
            "Hydrosphere",
            "Lithosphere",
            "Atmosphere"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Mariana is an example of ……………",
        "options": [
            "Beach",
            "Trench",
            "Plateau"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": " …………… rocks are formed due to the depositing of layers over layers.",
        "options": [
            "Sedimentary",
            "Igneous",
            "Granite"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Name the plateau in the Indian ocean.",
        "options": [
            "Deccan plateau",
            "Chagos plateau",
            "Marwar plateau"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Land submerged below the oceanic water is called the ……………",
        "options": [
            "Ocean floor",
            "Surface",
            "Plain"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": " Natural Gas and mineral oil is obtained from ……………",
        "options": [
            "Mumbai High",
            "Kolkata High",
            "Chennai High"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Earthquakes and volcanic eruption occurring in the ocean bed give rise to …………… in the nearby coastal areas",
        "options": [
            "High tides",
            "Tsunamis"
        ],
        "answer": 2 
    },
    {
        "question": " Name the land form Located between 200 m to 3600 meters with steep and narrow slope.",
        "options": [
            "Abyssal plain",
            "Continental slope",
            "Continental shelf"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": " Identify the correct option and complete the sentence : Abyssal plain consists of ……………",
        "options": [
            "Radio active material",
            "Rocks and pebbles",
            "Hills and plateau"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The continental shelf is …………… than the continental slope.",
        "options": [
            "Broader",
            "Narrow",
            "Sleeper"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The value of Mean Sea Level is ……………",
        "options": [
            "10 (ten)",
            "5 (five)",
            "0 (zero)"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": " The landforms on the earth are classified on the basis of ……………",
        "options": [
            "Height",
            "Depth",
            "Altitude"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The visible peak above sea level is called ……………",
        "options": [
            "Mountain",
            "Island",
            "Plateau"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Complete the statement : 200 meters below the sea level having shallowest sea in the ocean floor is ……………",
        "options": [
            "Marine deeps",
            "Marine trenches",
            "Continental shelf"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the odd one ou",
        "options": [
            "Vegetation",
            "Algae",
            "Plankton",
            "Marine tree"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the odd one.",
        "options": [
            "Marine deeps",
            "Continental slope",
            "Plains",
            "Island"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The landforms are named according to its …………… below water.",
        "options": [
            "Height",
            "Depth",
            "Width"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Indian island …………… have submerged peaks and mountains stretched for thousands of kilometers.",
        "options": [
            "Lakshadweep",
            "Andaman – Nicobar",
            "Dwarika"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Submerged hills and mountains are dangerous for the sailing of ships",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The land submerged in water near the coast is called ……………",
        "options": [
            "Continental slope",
            "Abyssal plain",
            "Continental Shelf"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The famous fishing ground is ……………",
        "options": [
            "Abyssal plain",
            "Continental slope",
            "Continental shelf"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    }
]